The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: We're going to cover hashing next time.
教授：下次我们将讨论散列。
Now we're Going to focus on pset three
现在我们将重点介绍pset第三
because I heard pset three is hard
因为我听说pset 3很难
so we're going to look at the code and try to understand it.
因此，我们将看一下代码并尝试理解它。
AUDIENCE: This course is hard.
听众：这门课很难。
PROFESSOR: I've tried to make it easy.
教授：我试图使其变得简单。
I really tried.
我真的尝试过
How many people recognize the code?
有多少人识别该密码？
Does this look familiar?
这看起来很熟悉吗？
One, two, three.
一二三。
Everyone else got stuck on question one?
其他人都陷入一个问题吗？
I'm not going to give you the answers to the psets.
我不会为您提供这些pset的答案。
We are going to--
我们准备去 -
AUDIENCE: [LAUGHING]
观众：[笑声]
PROFESSOR: Sorry.
教授：对不起。
We're going to look at the code and understand
我们将看一下代码并了解
what it does because once you understand what it does
它会做什么，因为一旦您了解了它的作用
you can understand how to modify it.
您可以了解如何进行修改。
All right, before I do that, any questions?
好吧，在我这样做之前，有什么问题吗？
And I might not answer them right away,
而且我可能不会立即回答他们，
but I will keep them in mind while I go through the code.
但是在阅读代码时，我会牢记它们。
Are there any specific pin-points.
是否有任何具体的要点。
AUDIENCE: The types.
听众：类型。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Covered in five minutes.
五分钟内覆盖。
Oh well.
那好吧。
The first thing that I want to talk about
我想谈的第一件事
is sweep line algorithms.
是扫线算法。
We're asking you to implement the sweep line algorithm
我们要求您实施扫线算法
and we're giving you one that is horribly inefficient.
我们正在为您提供效率极低的产品。
Suppose you have some line segments that look like this.
假设您有一些看起来像这样的线段。
Sorry, drawing isn't.
抱歉，不是。
They look like this.
他们看起来像这样。
And suppose you want to find the intersections between them.
并假设您想找到它们之间的交点。
Now let's figure out what the algorithm
现在让我们找出什么算法
that we gave you does.
我们给你的。
Did people look at the trace for that?
人们看到了这条痕迹吗？
Not the good trace, the trace that's output by the algorithm
不是好的跟踪，而是算法输出的跟踪
that we gave you.
我们给你的
Does anyone understand what that does.
有谁知道那是什么。
AUDIENCE: I kind of get it.
听众：我有点明白。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: I think what it does is it just hits through all
听众：我认为它的作用是贯穿所有人
the horizontal lines and it goes through all the vertical ones.
水平线，并穿过所有垂直线。
First it goes through all the horizontal lines
首先，它穿过所有水平线
and what does it do with them?
对他们有什么作用？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: They get bolded in the visualizer which
教授：他们在可视化工具中加粗了
means they're added to the range index.
表示将它们添加到范围索引中。
So one, add all the horizontal lines.
因此，添加所有水平线。
And two-- oh you said it goes through all the vertical lines
还有两个-哦，你说的是它贯穿所有垂直线
after that.
之后。
Any idea what it does?
知道它做什么吗？
AUDIENCE: It looks for intersections.
听众：它寻找路口。
PROFESSOR: When he looks at a vertical line segment
教授：当他看着垂直线段时
you'll see some blue square and you'll
你会看到一些蓝色方块，你会
see some segments that are green.
看到一些绿色的段。
This is a query to the range index
这是对范围索引的查询
and the green segments are the answers
绿色部分就是答案
and the blue square is the range that's queried.
蓝色正方形是要查询的范围。
First add all the segments to the range index
首先将所有细分添加到范围索引
and then do a query.
然后进行查询。
In principle sweep line algorithms
原则上扫线算法
have some geometric inputs.
有一些几何输入。
For example, a bunch of lines.
例如，一堆线。
And conceptually they have this vertical line
从概念上讲，他们有垂直线
that they sweep across the plane all the way from minus infinity
他们从负无穷处一直扫过飞机
to plus infinity.
加上无限。
Now if you try to sweep a line continuously
现在，如果您尝试连续扫描一条线
from minus infinity to plus infinity in code
从负无穷大到正无穷大
it might take forever.
这可能需要永远。
We don't really do it that way.
我们并不是真的那样做。
The way we do it in code is you know
我们在代码中执行此操作的方式是
when something interesting is going to happen
当一些有趣的事情要发生时
and you only simulate what happens to the sweep line
而且你只模拟扫掠线发生了什么
at that point.
在那时候。
In this case the sweep line starts at minus infinity
在这种情况下，扫描线始于负无穷大
and then all the horizontal segments
然后所有的水平线段
are added to our range index.
被添加到我们的范围索引中。
And then as the sweep line goes across the plane, when
然后当扫掠线越过飞机时，
it hits a vertical segment a query happens.
它碰到一个垂直段，查询就会发生。
The only times when the sweep line stops
扫线停止的唯一时间
is first, at the beginning to add all the horizontal line
首先，在开始时添加所有水平线
segments, and then every time it hits a vertical line segment.
线段，然后每次碰到垂直线段时
We know this ahead of time so we can
我们提前知道这一点，所以我们可以
compute a list of all these coordinates
计算所有这些坐标的列表
of interesting things.
有趣的事情。
And then we can sort them and then go through them
然后我们可以对它们进行排序，然后遍历它们
and simulate the behavior of the sweep line that way.
并以此方式模拟扫描线的行为。
If you look at the code listing at events from there,
如果您查看代码清单中发生的事件，
this is the gist of it.
这就是要点。
This is what it does.
这就是它的作用。
It compiles a list of events.
它编译事件列表。
The first key in each event is the x, is that x?
每个事件的第一个键是x，是x吗？
Yeah. x like this, y like this.
是的x像这样，y像这样。
The first case, the x-coordinate of an event
第一种情况，事件的x坐标
and by sorting that list of events
并通过排序事件列表
it will then process them in order.
然后它将按顺序处理它们。
Events from there is responsible for looking at all the wires
来自那里的事件负责查看所有连线
and compiling events.
和编译事件。
How does an event for a horizontal layer look like?
水平图层的事件看起来如何？
Can anyone tell me?
谁能告诉我？
Sorry, for a horizontal wire.
对不起，对于水平线。
AUDIENCE: It will run across [INAUDIBLE].
听众：它将跨[听不清]运行。
PROFESSOR: First off it looks like a list, right?
教授：首先，它看起来像一个列表，对吗？
It's a regular python list.
这是一个常规的python列表。
And I will try to call it vector so that we don't confuse it
我会尝试称其为向量，以便我们不会混淆它
with a big list of all the events.
包含所有事件的大清单。
You said the first thing is the leftmost point.
您说的第一件事是最左边的地方。
Right?
对？
If this segment, for example, starts at minus 100,
举例来说，如果这个区隔的开头是负100，
this one starts at minus 95, this one starts at minus 90,
这个从负95开始，这个从负90开始，
and this one starts at minus 50, by the way not to scale,
而这个开始于负50，顺便说一下，
then the leftmost point is minus 100.
那么最左边的点是负100。
Right?
对？
This is the first element in the vector.
这是向量中的第一个元素。
And that's computed on line four where
那是在第四行计算的
it goes through all the segments,
它遍及所有细分市场
looks at all the X-coordinates and chooses the minimum.
查看所有X坐标并选择最小值。
What's the next thing in the vector?
向量中的下一件事是什么？
We don't have to understand why.
我们不必了解原因。
We'll go through why in a bit.
我们稍后会详细说明为什么。
I'm just interested in what?
我只是对什么感兴趣？
AUDIENCE: Zero.
听众：零。
PROFESSOR: Zero.
教授：零。
Excellent.
优秀的。
PROFESSOR: After that there is a wire ID.
教授：之后有一个电线ID。
Each wire gets a unique ID, that's a number between zero
每条线都有一个唯一的ID，即介于零之间的数字
and the number of wires.
和电线数量。
Say this is one, two, three.
说这是一，二，三。
This is going to be one.
这将是一个。
And then I have the string add.
然后我有字符串添加。
And then I have the actual wire object.
然后我有了实际的电线对象。
What does the vector look like for a query event?
向量对于查询事件是什么样的？
Sorry, what does it look like for a vertical wire?
抱歉，垂直电线看起来像什么？
I'm giving away some of the answer.
我正在给出一些答案。
Bad, bad, bad.
不好不好
All right, vertical wire, look at the code and.
好的，垂直线，看代码和。
AUDIENCE: It keeps the left [INAUDIBLE].
听众：保持左侧[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Of the wire.
教授：电线。
OK.
好。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: It keeps the x-coordinate [INAUDIBLE].
听众：保持x坐标[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: A vertical wire will have the same X-coordinates
教授：垂直导线的X坐标相同
for all the points on the wire, right?
对于电线上的所有点，对不对？
I don't really worry about which coordinate it is.
我真的不担心它是什么坐标。
This wire is at minus 50.
该导线的负值为50。
The first element here is going to be minus 50.
这里的第一个元素将是负50。
What's next?
下一步是什么？
AUDIENCE: A 1.
听众：A 1。
PROFESSOR: A 1.
教授：A 1。
OK.
好。
And suppose this is wire ID 4.
并假设这是电线ID 4。
I'm going to have 4.
我要去4。
AUDIENCE: Query.
听众：查询。
PROFESSOR: Query.
教授：查询。
AUDIENCE: And the wire.
听众：还有电线。
PROFESSOR: And the wire.
教授：还有电线。
All right, what happens with these in the init method, which
好吧，在init方法中这些会发生什么，
is not shown in the code listing,
没有显示在代码清单中，
is after the list is put together sort is called on it.
是将列表放在一起后对它进行排序。
These are all compared and then reordered
比较所有这些，然后重新排序
to be sorted according to some ordering relationship.
根据某种排序关系进行排序。
Does anyone know what the ordering relationship
有谁知道订购关系
is for Python lists?
是用于Python列表？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: It starts from the first, from zero,
听众：从第一个开始，从零开始，
and the next it goes to sort the same with as X 1.
接下来，它的排序与X 1相同。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Say if I have 1, 2, 3 and 1, 3, 2.
假设我有1、2、3和1、3、2。
Sorry, and 2, 1, 2.
抱歉，还有2，1，2。
He's going to look at the first element
他要看第一个元素
and if they are different than the one with the smaller
如果它们与较小的那些不同
element is smaller.
元素较小。
1, 2, 3 as a vector, sorry, as a list,
1、2、3作为向量，对不起，作为列表，
is smaller than 2, 1, 2 as a list.
小于2、1、2作为列表。
If this guy becomes one then they're equal.
如果这个人成为一个人，那么他们是平等的。
Then it has to go to the next element,
然后必须转到下一个元素，
compare them and see if they're different we have
比较它们，看看它们是否不同
an answer, if not we have to keep
一个答案，如果没有，我们必须保持
going all the way until the end of the list.
一直到列表末尾。
This is called lexicographic comparison
这称为词典比较
and this is the same ordering that you have for the words
这与您对单词的排序相同
in a dictionary.
在字典中。
Right, if you think of each letter
是的，如果您想到每个字母
as an element in a list and the word is the list
作为列表中的元素，单词是列表
then this is how you look up words in a dictionary.
这就是您在字典中查找单词的方式。
The reason events look like this is
事件看起来像这样的原因是
so that sort would output them in the right order
这样排序将以正确的顺序输出
for the next state.
对于下一个状态。
So, yes.
所以，是的。
AUDIENCE: Does that mean all the horizontal wires,
听众：这是否意味着所有水平线，
does that mean that they start at same place even though that
这是否意味着即使他们
they don't?
他们不？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
all the horizontal wires will be sorted.
所有水平导线将被分类。
All these add events will be sorted before the query events.
所有这些添加事件将在查询事件之前进行排序。
Yup, very good observation.
是的，很好的观察。
This is what I'm trying to achieve.
这就是我要实现的目标。
That's why I have this special value here.
这就是为什么我在这里有这个特殊的价值。
I go through some extra effort to compute it.
我花了一些额外的精力来计算它。
I had to write an extra line of code
我不得不多写一行代码
so this is the motivation for it.
所以这就是它的动力。
The first key in the vector is the X element
向量中的第一个键是X元素
on the sweep line.
在清扫线上
I could've also had the very large negative value
我也可以拥有很大的负值
that something that would behave like minus infinity here
在这里表现为负无穷大的东西
and that would work just as well.
而且效果也一样。
By computing the left edge I don't have to deal with that.
通过计算左边缘，我不必处理。
I don't have to worry of whether my negative infinity is
我不必担心我的负无穷大是
small enough, because if it's not I will fail the test
足够小，因为如果不是，我将无法通过测试
and that's bad.
那很糟糕。
This is the x-coordinate at which the sweep line stops
这是扫掠线停止的x坐标
and something happens.
发生了一些事情。
So if all the events are different the x-coordinates
因此，如果所有事件都不相同，则x坐标
then I have my ordering, I'm done.
然后我下订单了，我完成了。
Now what if I have two events at the same time?
现在，如果我同时有两个事件怎么办？
For example, what if I have two vertical wires?
例如，如果我有两条垂直线怎么办？
The x-coordinates are going to be the same
x坐标将相同
so I need to use something else to break the ties, right?
所以我需要用别的东西打破平局，对吗？
The first thing that I use to break the ties
我打破关系的第一件事
is all add events have a zero here
是所有添加事件在这里都为零
and all the query events have a one.
并且所有查询事件都有一个。
And the point of that is if I have
关键是如果我有
two events at the same x-coordinate,
两个事件在相同的x坐标上
if I have a query and an add, I want
如果我有一个查询和一个添加，我想要
the add to happen before the query.
添加发生在查询之前。
If this is the same this is going
如果相同的话
to be different for ad versus query.
在广告和查询方面有所不同。
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
This is how we order events relatively
这是我们相对地订购事件的方式
to each other on the same line.
彼此在同一条线上。
Now suppose I have these two wires,
现在假设我有两条线，
they're both vertical so they're both going to be queries.
它们都是垂直的，因此它们都是查询。
They're both at the same index.
他们都在同一索引。
I need something else, and that other thing that I have
我需要其他东西，还有我拥有的其他东西
is the wire ID which is guaranteed to be unique.
是保证唯一的电线ID。
I know for sure the comparison will stop here.
我知道比较会在这里停止。
And the comparison had better stop here
比较最好在这里停止
because if the comparison gets all the way to here,
因为如果比较一直到这里
wires aren't comparable so the code is going to crash.
电线不具有可比性，因此代码将崩溃。
It stops here because the IDs are unique, everyone is happy.
因为ID是唯一的，所以每个人都很高兴，这里就停止了。
All right, do the events make more sense now?
好吧，这些事件现在有意义吗？
To complete the picture if you look
要看完整的图片
at compute crossings, lines nine and ten.
在计算交叉口，第9和10行。
Line nine goes through the vector-- sorry,
第9行经过向量-抱歉，
goes through the list of events that have been sorted
浏览已排序的事件列表
and processes them in order so sort
并按顺序处理它们
had better do the right job.
最好做正确的工作。
And then it extracts the x-coordinate, that's here,
然后提取x坐标，就在这里，
it extracts the event type, that's here,
它提取事件类型，就在这里，
and then it extracts the wire from here.
然后从这里提取电线。
These guys really are just there to help with the sorting,
这些家伙真的在那里帮助您进行分类，
they're never read afterwards.
他们以后再也不会阅读。
AUDIENCE: Where are the events actually sort?
听众：这些事件实际上在哪里排序？
I thought they just put into order.
我以为他们只是整理好了。
PROFESSOR: The events are sorted in an init method that's
教授：这些事件按以下方法的init方法排序：
not here.
不在这里。
It's in the piece of code but it's not here.
它在代码段中，但不在这里。
And that may be a hint that you don't want to change it.
这可能暗示您不想更改它。
As in you don't need to.
就像您不需要的那样。
All right, events look like this.
好吧，事件看起来像这样。
Any questions about events?
对活动有任何疑问吗？
Everything make sense?
一切都有意义吗？
Presumably when you write your own sweep line algorithm
大概是在编写自己的扫掠线算法时
you're going to come up with your own events which
您将提出自己的事件
are going to be different.
将会有所不同。
You're going to change these methods to add
您将更改这些方法以添加
your own events to the list.
您自己的事件进入列表。
And then it's going to be sorted for you
然后将为您进行排序
and then you're going to change compute crossings to process
然后您将更改计算交叉以进行处理
your events in the way that they should be processed.
您的事件的处理方式。
Let's look at the range index.
让我们看一下范围索引。
What do we store in a range index?
我们在范围索引中存储什么？
AUDIENCE: The horizontal wires.
听众：水平线。
PROFESSOR: Horizontal wires.
教授：水平线。
Very good.
很好。
What's the point of storing horizontal wires in an index?
将水平线存储在索引中有什么意义？
AUDIENCE: That's when you want to query,
听众：那是您要查询的时候，
the area has a line through it.
该区域有一条线穿过。
PROFESSOR: For the algorithm that we gave you
教授：对于我们给您的算法
how does a query look like?
查询看起来如何？
Suppose I have this wire here and I'm doing a query for it.
假设我在这里有这根线，并且正在对其进行查询。
AUDIENCE: Just ask to list horizontal wires that
听众：只要求列出水平线
are between that Y.
在那个Y之间。
PROFESSOR: Between this guy's top and this guy's bottom.
教授：在这个人的顶部和这个人的底部之间。
Right?
对？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: A query would look like this.
教授：查询看起来像这样。
Basically all the horizontal wires
基本上所有的水平线
that have their y-coordinates between this guy and this guy.
在这个家伙和这个家伙之间有y坐标
Now if I have a wire that's way up here or way down here
现在，如果我的电线在这里或在这里
I know for sure that it's not going to intersect this wire.
我确定它不会与这条线相交。
Right?
对？
I don't care about it.
我不在乎。
The range index helps me eliminate some wires.
范围索引可帮助我消除一些导线。
Now, will the range index eliminate all the wires
现在，范围索引会消除所有导线吗
that don't intersect with this wire?
不与这根线相交？
No, OK.
不行
Why not?
为什么不？
AUDIENCE: Well in this code it doesn't.
听众：在这段代码中没有。
PROFESSOR: OK, in this code it doesn't.
教授：好的，在此代码中没有。
We're only talking about this code,
我们只是在谈论这段代码，
I'm not talking about the solution code
我不是在说解决方案代码
that you guys have to implement.
你们必须实现。
AUDIENCE: It doesn't because it never
听众：不是因为从来没有
removes the horizontal wires.
移除水平导线。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What's an example of a query that would give me
可以给我一个查询的例子是什么
some wires that don't intersect my wire?
一些不与我的电线相交的电线？
AUDIENCE: Like if they're in between the y-axis,
听众：就像它们位于y轴之间一样，
they're, yeah but they're not actually.
是的，但实际上并非如此。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So you mean.
所以你的意思是
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Negative infinity and infinity on the x-axis
观众：x轴上的负无穷大和无穷大
would give you a bunch of wires and not many of them
会给你一堆电线，但不会很多
will intersect with the vertical wires.
将与垂直线相交。
AUDIENCE: If the end were a vertical wire, [INAUDIBLE].
听众：如果末端是垂直线，则[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
I understood this because it matches what I drew.
我理解这一点是因为它与我绘制的内容匹配。
I didn't understand the minus infinity plus infinity.
我不明白负无穷大和无穷大。
AUDIENCE: Well if you think about the x-axis on the bottom,
观众：好吧，如果您考虑底部的x轴，
if you go from all the way on the left to all the way
如果您从左边一直走到一直
on the right you're going to get a whole bunch of wires that are
在右边，您将获得一堆电线
short that--
简而言之-
PROFESSOR: Are you talking about one wire
教授：您在谈论一根电线吗？
that's like that, or many?
就是那样，还是很多？
AUDIENCE: If you're grabbing from your range index.
听众：如果您要从范围索引中获取信息。
PROFESSOR: The range index has horizontal wires in it.
教授：范围索引中有水平导线。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
AUDIENCE: Are you assuming that they're all short?
听众：您是否假设它们都很矮？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
But it's not necessarily true.
但这不一定是真的。
Some of them will be short.
其中一些会很短。
PROFESSOR: You're saying a lot of short horizontal lines--
教授：您说的是很多短的水平线-
you mean like this, right?
你的意思是这样吧？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
That's what you mean.
那就是你的意思
AUDIENCE: You have one intersection and--
听众：您有一个十字路口，而且-
PROFESSOR: A ton of non-intersections.
教授：大量的不交叉口。
AUDIENCE: Exactly.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK, cool.
教授：好的，很酷。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Doing a range query on this can give me
对此进行范围查询可以给我
a lot of false positives.
很多误报。
That's why after I get them I have
这就是为什么我得到他们之后
to make sure that they intersect and I
确保他们和我相交
can't just blindly output them.
不能盲目输出它们。
These are bad false positives, these are bad false positive.
这些都是错误的误报，这些都是错误的误报。
Now let's look at how the range index works.
现在让我们看看范围索引是如何工作的。
Can anyone remind me of what the range index does?
谁能提醒我范围索引的作用？
It's a data structure, right?
这是一个数据结构，对不对？
And it has some operations.
并且它有一些操作。
What are the operations for it?
它的作用是什么？
AUDIENCE: It returns everything between two values.
听众：它返回两个值之间的所有值。
PROFESSOR: You have a list operation where you give it
教授：您在其中进行列表操作
two values and it will return everything inside the index,
两个值，它将返回索引中的所有内容，
in the interval between those two values.
在这两个值之间的间隔中。
What else can I do?
我还可以做些什么？
AUDIENCE: It can also tell you how many.
听众：它也可以告诉您有多少。
It returns those keys and how many there are.
它返回这些键以及有多少键。
PROFESSOR: I have the count and you
教授：我有伯爵，你
said that I have some things in the index.
说我索引中有一些东西。
Right?
对？
How do I get them in there?
我怎样才能把他们带到那里？
These are queries, I need updates.
这些是查询，我需要更新。
AUDIENCE: Add and remove.
听众：添加和删除。
PROFESSOR: For the code that they gave you,
教授：对于他们给您的代码，
what is the running time for each of these operations?
这些操作的运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: It would be constant had to be removed.
听众：必须将其删除。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Add calls the pend.
添加呼叫待命。
Right?
对？
So that is constant.
因此，这是恒定的。
I will agree there.
我会同意的。
AUDIENCE: To remove it you had to shift everything.
听众：要删除它，您必须转移所有内容。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Let's start with an example.
让我们从一个例子开始。
Say I have these keys in my range index.
假设我在范围索引中有这些键。
5, 8, 11, 13.
5、8、11、13
Suppose they're magically inserted in this order.
假设以这种顺序神奇地插入了它们。
If I want to remove two, since this is an array
如果我要删除两个，因为这是一个数组
I have to shift everything to the left.
我必须将所有内容向左移动。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So that's.
教授：就是这样。
AUDIENCE: Order and time.
听众：顺序和时间。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
How about list and counts?
列表和计数如何？
What's the running time for counts?
计数的运行时间是多少？
How does count work?
计数如何工作？
AUDIENCE: It's not just through all of the keys.
听众：不只是通过所有按键。
PROFESSOR: Count goes through everything and--
教授：数不胜数，而且-
AUDIENCE: It has to be order [INAUDIBLE].
听众：必须定购[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
Count goes through all the keys, evaluates
计数遍历所有关键，评估
the predicate that checks whether they're in the range
检查它们是否在范围内的谓词
and then it adds up one to the sum for the right place.
然后将其加到正确位置的总和。
How about list?
清单怎么样？
AUDIENCE: Also [INAUDIBLE].
听众：也[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, that's a list comprehension.
教授：好的，这是一个列表理解。
The code is a bit tricky, but it pretty much
该代码有点棘手，但几乎
does the same thing.
做同样的事情。
It goes through the list and it puts all the keys
它遍历列表，并放入所有键
that are in the interval in the list.
在列表中的时间间隔中。
Now let's look at another version
现在让我们看看另一个版本
on the next page of our range index that is slightly better.
在范围索引的下一页上会略好一些。
What's the rapid variance for this?
快速变化是什么？
How is it different from the first one?
与第一个有何不同？
AUDIENCE: Sorted already.
观众：已经排序。
PROFESSOR: Sorted already.
教授：已经排序。
Very good.
很好。
The keys look exactly like this.
键看起来完全像这样。
Right?
对？
What is the running time for-- let's start with add or remove,
运行时间是多少？让我们从添加或删除开始，
what's the running time for add and remove?
添加和删​​除的运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: N, order of N.
听众：N，N的阶数。
PROFESSOR: Why is it order of N?
教授：为什么是N阶？
AUDIENCE: No, oder log N.
听众：否，输入对数N。
PROFESSOR: Why is it order log N.
教授：为什么要订购日志N。
AUDIENCE: Because if it's sorted you can look in the middle
观众：因为如果排序的话，您可以在中间查看
and do a binary search.
并进行二进制搜索。
PROFESSOR: I can do a binary search in order
教授：我可以按顺序进行二进制搜索
to find out where I insert something.
找出我在哪里插入东西。
Right?
对？
But what if I want to insert zero in this?
但是，如果我想在其中插入零怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Is it log N plus order N?
听众：是对数N加上顺序N？
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
Because you have to shift all of the [INAUDIBLE].
因为您必须转移所有[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So worst case if I have to insert zero here,
所以最糟糕的情况是如果我必须在此处插入零，
I have to shift everything to the right to make room for it.
我必须将所有内容移至右侧以为其腾出空间。
Right?
对？
So your first instinct was good.
所以你的第一个直觉是好的。
Order N. And questions?
订单N。还有问题吗？
No more?
不再？
Cool.
凉。
How about remove?
如何删除？
AUDIENCE: Order N.
观众：N号订单。
PROFESSOR: Order N. Why is it order N?
教授：N阶。为什么是N阶？
AUDIENCE: You have to shift left everything to the right.
听众：您必须将所有内容向左移动。
PROFESSOR: Is this what you were going to say too?
教授：这也是您要说的吗？
Same reason as before, if I want to remove 2
如果要删除2，原因与以前相同
I still have to move everything to the left.
我仍然必须将所有内容移到左侧。
I can find the key that I want to remove very fast
我可以很快找到想要删除的密钥
but then shifting things is still
但是转移事物仍然是
order N. OK how about count?
订购N。好吧，算一下吗？
How does count work?
计数如何工作？
AUDIENCE: It's the same thing, isn't it?
听众：是同一回事，不是吗？
AUDIENCE: Binary search so it's log n.
听众：二进制搜索，因此为n。
PROFESSOR: Binary search, so it's log n.
教授：二进制搜索，因此为n。
If I look at the count there it's--
如果我看一下伯爵，那是-
AUDIENCE: It's not though, that's
听众：不是，那是
telling you how many keys between.
告诉您之间有多少键。
AUDIENCE: So it's a simple subtraction
听众：这是一个简单的减法
to find the number of keys between.
查找之间的键数。
PROFESSOR: Count calls binary search twice
教授：计数两次调用二进制搜索
and then it does a arithmetic operation, yes.
然后执行算术运算，是的。
AUDIENCE: It would be log n because with the count where
观众：这是log n，因为计数在哪里
the range is that's log n because you have to actually
范围是log n，因为您必须实际
sift through it, but binary search you have two
通过它进行筛选，但是二进制搜索有两个
other operations and then you just do a surprise.
其他操作，然后您会感到惊讶。
PROFESSOR: Yep, thank you.
教授：是的，谢谢。
Very good.
很好。
This is log n because of good old binary search.
由于良好的旧二进制搜索，因此这是log n。
How about lists?
列表呢？
I think you were thinking ahead of lists.
我认为您在考虑清单之前。
How about lists?
列表呢？
AUDIENCE: You have to list every single thing that you read.
听众：您必须列出您阅读的每件事。
AUDIENCE: You've got the values you might potentially
听众：您已经拥有了潜在的价值
have to [INAUDIBLE].
必须[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: Is it log n plus the length of the list.
听众：是log n加上列表的长度。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
I was going to do a nice long analysis
我打算做一个很好的长期分析
and there's the answer.
答案就在那里。
Log n plus, suppose you return i values from the list, i.
登录n加号，假设您从列表i返回i值。
Why does this matter?
为什么这么重要？
If I have a range query from minus infinity to plus infinity
如果我有从负无穷大到正无穷大的范围查询
I have to create a new list, copy all these keys in
我必须创建一个新列表，将所有这些键复制到
and return them.
并退还给他们。
That's order n.
那是命令n。
I can't just say it's log n.
我不能只说它是log n。
On the other hand, if the answers to my list queries
另一方面，如果我列表的答案查询
are small, if they're one element,
很小，如果它们是一个要素，
then it's going to take log n time to do a binary search
那么将需要log n的时间来进行二进制搜索
and then order one to produce the list if I
然后如果我订购一个来产生清单
have a constant size list.
具有固定的尺寸列表。
If I just say order n I'm selling myself short.
如果我只说订单n，我就是卖空自己。
It's a lot better if I want to have short queries.
如果我想简短查询，那就更好了。
What would be the best possible running time for lists?
列表的最佳运行时间是什么？
If I had a magic algorithm that works as fast as possible would
如果我有一个魔术算法可以尽快工作
I be able to run in order one time?
我可以一次运行吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: Super fast magic algorithm order one.
教授：超快速魔术算法排名第一。
No, why not?
不，为什么不呢？
AUDIENCE: Because you still have to find l and h in your array.
听众：因为您仍然必须在数组中找到l和h。
PROFESSOR: Suppose I have some other data
教授：假设我还有其他数据
structure, a super magical data structure.
结构，超级神奇的数据结构。
AUDIENCE: You can do searches in order one time,
听众：您可以一次搜索一次，
is what you're saying.
是你的意思
AUDIENCE: You still have to have the contents of it
听众：您仍然必须拥有其中的内容
for what you're listing.
您要列出的内容。
It would have to be order i.
它必须是命令i。
PROFESSOR: Even if I have a super magical data
教授：即使我有超级神奇的数据
structure where I can do everything that I want inside
我可以在其中做我想做的所有事情的结构
in order one time then when I produce the output
然后一次当我产生输出时
I still have to write the output.
我仍然必须写输出。
This thing is going to be omega i
这东西将会是欧米茄我
and I can't possibly do any better than that.
我不可能做得更好。
No matter what running time you have
无论您有多长时间
for list it has to include this i.
对于列表，它必须包括这个。
Unless you're running time is order i, in which case
除非您的跑步时间是订单i，在这种情况下
i is smaller or equal to n.
i小于或等于n。
Does this look right to you?
这看起来合适吗？
There is a small bug in this code.
此代码中有一个小错误。
What if I do count of 4, 11.
如果我算4、11怎么办？
Binary search returns, if there's a key
如果有密钥，则返回二进制搜索
there it will give me the position of that key.
在那里，它将给我该钥匙的位置。
And if there's no key it will tell me
如果没有钥匙，它将告诉我
where I should insert the key if the key doesn't
如果没有，我应该在哪里插入钥匙
exist in theory.
在理论上存在。
So if this is my array then the positions are 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
因此，如果这是我的数组，则位置为0、1、2、3、4、5。
Count of 4, 11 would do a binary search of 11 and see 4
计数4、11将对11进行二进制搜索并查看4
and then it will do a binary search for 4 and return 2.
然后它将对4进行二进制搜索并返回2。
Right?
对？
Because if I want to insert 4 I would
因为如果我要插入4，我会
have to put it here and then shift everything to the right.
必须将其放在此处，然后将所有内容移至右侧。
And 4 minus 2 is 2 therefore it's broken.
4减2是2，所以它被破坏了。
AUDIENCE: Off by one block.
听众：减少一格。
PROFESSOR: Off by one block, right?
教授：分开一格，对吗？
Well the interesting thing about it is that I had this code,
有趣的是，我有这段代码，
we actually shipped this code between Saturday morning
我们实际上在星期六早上之间发送了此代码
and Sunday evening and it passed all the tests.
和周日晚上，它通过了所有测试。
As we go to the next section keep in mind
当我们转到下一部分时，请记住
that this is broken but it would still
这是坏的，但它仍然会
pass the test for our problem and we'll see why in a bit.
通过测试以解决我们的问题，稍后我们将了解原因。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Count of 4, 11.
教授：数4、11。
AUDIENCE: So confined to them then
听众：当时仅限于他们
it says that when you're down 5, right?
它说当你情绪低落的时候5，对吗？
Four.
四。
PROFESSOR: Four.
教授：四。
Binary search, if it finds the key
二进制搜索（如果找到密钥）
it returns the position of they key.
它返回键的位置。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] 4 divided by x, and 4,
观众：[听不清] 4除以x，再加上4，
4 would it have had two?
4它会有两个？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, because it tells me where to insert it.
教授：是的，因为它告诉我在哪里插入。
AUDIENCE: OK, then it is.
听众：好的，是的。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Well it says 4 minus 2, right?
教授：好吧，是4减2，对不对？
The last line is high index minus low index?
最后一行是高指数减去低指数？
AUDIENCE: Oh, well that's wrong. [INAUDIBLE].
听众：哦，那是错误的。 [听不清]。
AUDIENCE: So are you saying that it tells you where to insert it
观众：您是说它告诉您插入位置
instead of actually inserting it.
而不是实际插入。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Binary search doesn't insert the element.
二进制搜索不会插入该元素。
It just tells me this is where you put it.
它只是告诉我这是您放置的位置。
And then if you look at add, add inserts it right there.
然后，如果您查看添加，添加将在此处插入。
That's why binary search is done that way
这就是为什么以这种方式进行二进制搜索
so that that would work.
这样就可以了。
AUDIENCE: Can I ask a style question?
听众：我可以问一个风格问题吗？
PROFESSOR: Sure.
教授：当然可以。
AUDIENCE: The underscore before binary search,
听众：二进制搜索前的下划线，
is that like saying private?
像是私下说吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
AUDIENCE: Wait, what does private mean?
听众：等等，私人意味着什么？
PROFESSOR: Private means that it's not
教授：私人意味着不是
part of the public interface of the class.
该类的公共接口的一部分。
If we're in a team and we're working on something,
如果我们在团队中并且正在做某事，
if I mark a method as private that means if you use my class,
如果我将方法标记为私有，则意味着如果您使用我的课程，
you're not supposed to call it because I might change
你不应该叫它，因为我可能会改变
it's name, I might delete it completely,
它的名字，我可能会完全删除它，
I can do anything I want to it.
我可以做任何我想做的事。
But if the method is public, so add, remove, list, and count,
但是，如果该方法是公开的，那么添加，删除，列出和计数，
those are the API or the public interface of the class.
这些是该类的API或公共接口。
I guarantee that as long as the blit range index class exists
我保证只要blit range索引类存在
it's going to have an add to remove a list
它会有一个添加来删除列表
and the conduct will behave in exactly in that way.
行为将完全按照这种方式行事。
Once you have a class with public methods
一旦有了公共方法的类
you're not supposed to change them
你不应该改变他们
because other people might depend on them
因为其他人可能依赖他们
and that would make other people unhappy.
那会让其他人不高兴。
We said that this range index holds wires.
我们说这个范围指数包含电线。
Right?
对？
So if you have these wires here they're not really numbers.
因此，如果您在这里使用这些导线，它们并不是真正的数字。
I know how to compare numbers, I don't
我知道如何比较数字，我不知道
know how to compare wires.
知道如何比较电线。
That's not something that's readily comparable, right?
那不是可以立即比较的东西，对吗？
We have to bridge the gap between numbers or things
我们必须弥合数字或事物之间的鸿沟
that are comparable and wires.
可比的和电线。
The way we do that is the key wire pair class.
我们这样做的方法是关键线对类。
If you look at key wire pair class
如果看钥匙线对类
it has-- I will write it as KWP here.
它有-我将在此处将其编写为KWP。
So it has a key and the wire.
因此，它具有钥匙和电线。
Right?
对？
That's why it's a key wire pair.
这就是为什么它是关键线对。
And if you look at the comparison methods,
如果您看一下比较方法，
lines 11 through 26, but if you look at 11
第11至26行，但如果您看一下11
through 13 pretty much everything else is the same.
至13几乎其他所有内容都是相同的。
Then comparisons are done in a certain way.
然后以某种方式进行比较。
So the first criterion is the key.
因此，第一个标准是关键。
If you have two key wire pairs that have different keys,
如果您有两个具有不同按键的按键线对，
then the one with the bigger key wins.
那么拥有较大钥匙的那个人将获胜。
Now if they have the same key then
现在，如果它们具有相同的密钥，则
this field called wire IDs is used to break ties.
此字段称为“电线ID”用于打破平局。
So first key and then wire ID.
因此，首先要输入密钥，然后再输入导线ID。
What's the wire ID set to?
电线ID设置为什么？
And where?
在哪
Where would you set a field in a nice class?
您会在哪里安排好班级的课程？
AUDIENCE: The constructor.
听众：构造函数。
PROFESSOR: In the constructor, very good.
教授：在构造函数中，非常好。
Where is it set?
在哪里设置？
Line number?
电话号码？
AUDIENCE: 10.
听众：10。
PROFESSOR: Line 10.
教授：第10行。
So the wire ID uses the same object IDs that we had earlier.
因此，导线ID使用与之前相同的对象ID。
So each wire has a unique ID that's between zero
因此，每根导线都有一个介于零之间的唯一ID
and the number of wires.
和电线数量。
This works when I insert my wires into the index.
当我将电线插入索引时，此方法有效。
What's the key for wires, by the way?
顺便问一下，电线的关键是什么？
Where are wires inserted into the index in the algorithm
算法中将电线插入索引的位置
that we have and what's the key?
我们拥有什么，关键是什么？
The algorithm that we gave you.
我们给您的算法。
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: The y-coordinates.
听众：y坐标。
PROFESSOR: The?
教授：那个？
Which one, I couldn't hear you.
哪一个，我听不到您的声音。
AUDIENCE: The y-coordinate.
听众：y坐标。
PROFESSOR: The y-coordinate.
教授：y坐标。
Can you tell me which line?
你能告诉我哪条线吗？
The intuition is very good.
直觉非常好。
You want the wires to be keyed by the y-coordinate
您希望电线由y坐标锁定
so that when you a range query between this guy and this guy
这样当您在这个人和这个人之间进行范围查询时
you get these wires.
你得到这些电线。
That's the intuition.
这是直觉。
Now what's the code?
现在的代码是什么？
AUDIENCE: Line 13.
观众：第13行。
PROFESSOR: Line?
教授：行吗？
I didn't hear you well.
我听不太清楚。
Line?
线？
AUDIENCE: 13.
听众：13。
PROFESSOR: 13.
教授：13。
Wires are added to the index when an event of type
当类型为事件的导线被添加到索引
add is processed.
添加已处理。
Right?
对？
Line 12 says if event type is add
第12行说明是否添加了事件类型
so that's probably what we want.
所以这可能就是我们想要的。
And line 13 adds it to the index and builds the key wire repair
第13行将其添加到索引中，并构建关键线修复
with the key, the y-coordinate of the wire.
用键，导线的y坐标。
Now let's look back at the keys and see
现在让我们回顾一下按键，看看
that we have two special key wire repair classes.
我们有两个特殊的钥匙线维修课程。
Key wire pair l and key wire pair h.
钥匙线对l和钥匙线对h。
These don't want the wire.
这些不需要电线。
Why would I make a wire key pair that doesn't want the wire?
为什么要制作不需要电线的电线钥匙对？
Why is that useful?
为什么这样有用？
AUDIENCE: You have the minimum and maximum wire at ease.
听众：您轻松拥有最小和最大的电线。
PROFESSOR: Very good observation.
教授：非常好的观察。
The wire ID for the low key pair looks
低键对的电线ID看起来
like minus infinity and the one for the high key pair
如负无穷大和高键对之一
look like plus infinity as long as I
看起来像加无限，只要我
don't have more than a billion wires.
电线不超过十亿。
What do these things not have?
这些东西没有什么？
They don't have a wire.
他们没有电线。
So if you look at key wire pair l and h,
因此，如果您看一下关键线对l和h，
if you look at the initializers on lines two and eight,
如果您看第二和第八行的初始化程序，
they only take a key they don't take a wire.
他们只需要一把钥匙，而不需要电线。
This is useful in which situation?
这在哪种情况下有用？
Where do I want to create an index key that's
我要在哪里创建索引键
not associated with the real wire?
不与真正的电线关联？
AUDIENCE: When you want to make the list when
听众：当你想做清单的时候
you want to do a query.
您想查询。
PROFESSOR: When I do a query.
教授：我进行查询时。
Very good.
很好。
If I'm querying, if I have this vertical wire, which
如果要查询，是否有垂直线，
starts from minus 80 to plus 80 then I
从负80到正80开始，然后我
would like to make a low key that corresponds to minus 80
想做一个对应于负80的低调
and a high key that corresponds to plus 80,
和对应于加号80的高键，
but I don't have any wire with a horizontal coordinate of 80.
但我没有水平坐标为80的电线。
Right?
对？
A hackish solution would be to make
一个棘手的解决方案是
fake wires with those coordinates
假电线与那些坐标
but if I make fake wires God knows where my system is going
但是如果我制造假电线，上帝就会知道我的系统要去哪里
to break elsewhere.
在其他地方休息。
Instead the clean solution is to have these key wire pairs
相反，干净的解决方案是让这些关键线对
so that when I insert wires I have a wire
这样，当我插入电线时，我就有一根电线
and when I don't the wire is set to none.
而当我不这样做时，电线设置为无。
And the wire IDs are these special values,
电线ID是这些特殊值，
minus infinity and plus infinity.
负无穷大和正无穷大。
What's cool about setting the wire IDs to minus infinity
将电线ID设置为负无穷大是很酷的
and plus infinity?
加上无限？
AUDIENCE: It's so that if you have a y of 80
听众：如果您年满80岁
this y is at negative infinity so it's
这个y是负无穷大，所以
going to take that y also because its y value is
也会取那个y，因为它的y值是
[INAUDIBLE].
[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Cool.
凉。
If I have a real key wire pair and it
如果我有真正的钥匙线对，
has a wire whose coordinate is 80
导线的坐标为80
this is going to be bigger than a key wire pair
这将比钥匙线对更大
l with coordinate 80 and it's going
我的坐标是80
to be smaller than a key wire pair h with coordinate 80.
比具有坐标80的钥匙线对h小。
If you do a query using this and this
如果您使用此查询进行查询
it's going to grab all the wires with coordinate 80.
它将抓住坐标为80的所有导线。
Does this makes sense?
这有意义吗？
So what's cool about this in terms of coding?
那么，就编码而言，有什么很棒的呢？
Do I have equal keys in my range index?
范围索引中是否有相同的键？
Do I have to handle multiple equal keys?
我必须处理多个相等的键吗？
AUDIENCE: No because, actually in this case yes.
听众：否，因为在这种情况下实际上是。
PROFESSOR: Do I?
教授：可以吗？
AUDIENCE: Because if you have all the horizontal wires
听众：因为如果您有所有水平导线
then it's possible that you have two
那么你可能有两个
horizontal wires at the same--
同一水平线
PROFESSOR: If I have two horizontal wires,
教授：如果我有两条水平线，
say this guy here and this other guy
在这里说这个人和另一个人
here, this guy here, what's the key value pair for it?
在这里，这个人在这里，关键是什么？
Key wire pair?
钥匙线对？
Let's say the coordinate is minus 95 and the wire ID is 2.
假设坐标为负95，导线ID为2。
The key wire pair is they key is minus 95
关键线对是他们的关键是负95
and the wire ID is 2, right?
电线ID为2，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: And then for this other wire,
教授：然后，对于另一条线，
suppose the wire ID is 10, the coordinate is
假设导线ID为10，坐标为
going to be minus 95 then the wire ID is going to be 10.
减为95，则导线ID为10。
So how are they going to compare?
那么他们将如何比较？
AUDIENCE: Then that one is less than that one.
听众：那么那个小于那个。
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So even though I have two wires with the same y-coordinates
因此，即使我有两条线的y坐标相同
of the key as far as the algorithm is concerned
关于算法的密钥
is the same, in the implementation
在实现上是一样的
the keys are artificially different because I introduce
键是人为的，因为我介绍了
an artificial ordering on the wires using that wire ID.
使用该电线ID对电线进行人工订购。
In Which case would I have the same key inserted in my index
在那种情况下，我会在索引中插入相同的密钥
twice?
两次？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
If these two wires overlap, say this guy ends here
如果这两根线重叠，说这个家伙到此为止
and this guy ends here, and if I put their keys into the index
这个家伙到此结束，如果我把他们的钥匙放入索引
they're still different.
他们仍然不同。
AUDIENCE: Only if they're the same wire ID would
听众：只有它们的电线ID相同
they have the same--
他们有相同的-
PROFESSOR: OK, and when do two wires have the same wire ID?
教授：好的，两条线何时具有相同的线号？
AUDIENCE: If one of them was negative infinity.
听众：如果其中之一是负无穷大。
PROFESSOR: Let's assume that the infinities
教授：让我们假设无穷
were in the right way.
是正确的方式。
Yes?
是？
No?
没有？
Wire IDs are unique.
电线ID是唯一的。
Every wire has it's own wire ID.
每条电线都有自己的电线ID。
Wires will never have the same wire ID.
电线永远不会具有相同的电线ID。
So the only case in which you have
所以唯一的情况是
two equal keys in the index is if you insert the same wire
索引中的两个相等的键是如果您插入相同的导线
twice.
两次。
Would you ever want to do that?
您是否愿意这样做？
Probably not.
可能不是。
You're going to the same wire twice from the range query
您要通过范围查询两次访问同一条导线
and that's not useful.
这没有用。
When implementing a data structure for the range index
为范围索引实现数据结构时
we don't have to deal with equal keys
我们不必使用相同的键
and that is nice because that's less thinking.
那很好，因为这没什么想法。
Now when we do a query, will the keys in the query
现在，当我们执行查询时，查询中的键
be in the range index?
在范围索引内？
AUDIENCE: Not necessarily.
听众：不一定。
PROFESSOR: How would I do a query
教授：我将如何查询
if I want to do a query from minus 80 to plus 80?
如果我要从负80到正80进行查询？
AUDIENCE: You grab all the horizontal wires whose
观众：您抓住所有水平线，
y-coordinates are--
y坐标为-
PROFESSOR: You're thinking in the range index.
教授：您正在考虑范围索引。
I'm thinking as the client of the range index.
我在想作为范围索引的客户。
So you have this range index class,
所以你有这个范围索引类，
how would you issue a query to the range index?
您将如何向范围索引发出查询？
AUDIENCE: The list on this page.
听众：此页面上的列表。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
I would call the list method.
我将调用list方法。
And-- oh crap, I thought I was going
而且-糟糕，我以为我要去
to avoid doing that today.
避免今天这样做。
l and h are keys, right?
l和h是键，对不对？
How do I construct my keys?
我该如何构造我的钥匙？
AUDIENCE: Use key wire pair.
听众：使用钥匙线对。
PROFESSOR: Key wire pair left of 80--
教授：钥匙线对的左侧80--
sorry low, and key wire pair high of 80.
对不起低，关键线对高80。
So then I'm going to get to these--
因此，我将介绍这些内容-
I don't have wires for this 80 coordinate.
我没有用于该80坐标的导线。
Sorry, minus 80 to 80 because that's
抱歉，要减去80到80，因为
what the query looks like.
查询的样子。
I don't have wires for these coordinates
我没有这些坐标线
so I'm going to use these special values
所以我将使用这些特殊值
and this one is smaller than all the wires with coordinate
并且这比所有具有坐标的电线都小
minus 80 and this one is bigger than all
减80，这个比所有的都大
the wires with coordinate 80.
坐标为80的电线。
Will these keys ever be in the index?
这些键是否会出现在索引中？
Nope, we're only using them for updates.
不，我们仅将它们用于更新。
If you put this in the index then when
如果将其放在索引中，则何时
you're getting it back and you try to get the wire associated
您将其取回，并尝试获取关联的电线
with it you're going to get none,
有了它，你将一无所获，
your code is going to crash.
您的代码将崩溃。
If I have a query will the keys in the query ever
如果我有查询，查询中的键是否会
being the index?
是索引？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
That means fewer border cases to consider
这意味着需要考虑的边境案件更少
when implementing query.
在实现查询时。
All the keys in the range index are different
范围索引中的所有键都不相同
and they keys in the query will never be in the range index.
并且它们在查询中的键将永远不在范围索引中。
AUDIENCE: When you do the count l
听众：当你做点数
and h aren't in your range index you have to count that.
并且h不在您的范围索引中，您必须进行计数。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
In this case that's why the code didn't fail any test.
在这种情况下，这就是代码没有通过任何测试的原因。
Because I'm not using numbers I'm actually using this.
因为我没有使用数字，所以实际上是在使用数字。
So for the number analogy this is
因此，对于数字类比，这是
equivalent to when I'm doing a count of 4,11 that
等于我做4,11时
would get rewritten as count of 3, 99 and 11.01 and this works.
将被重写为3、99和11.01的计数，并且可以正常工作。
This is what these two values are doing.
这就是这两个值的作用。
Except if you try to do 0.99 and 0.01
除非您尝试执行0.99和0.01
that's brittle because you might actually have those keys.
这很脆弱，因为您实际上可能拥有这些键。
All right, does this make sense?
好吧，这有意义吗？
Any questions on this part?
对这部分有任何疑问吗？
Nope?
不？
Yes?
是？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: Is this thing in a count off situation
听众：这件事在盘算中吗
where you have a gap in the wires
电线上有空隙
but you still have a [INAUDIBLE] associated with it
但您仍然有一个[音频不清晰]
as it's going through it.
因为它正在经历。
PROFESSOR: Sorry, say that again.
教授：对不起，再说一遍。
AUDIENCE: So with that example right there.
听众：所以有了那个例子。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
PROFESSOR: Are you worried about the fact
教授：您是否担心这个事实
that I'll have two equal keys or are you worried about the fact
我有两个相等的钥匙，或者您担心这个事实
that these wires are crossing?
这些电线交叉吗？
AUDIENCE: No that they're not overlapping.
听众：不，它们没有重叠。
You have a wire and you have a wire coming down
你有电线，电线掉下来
and you have another wire.
你还有另一根电线。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
This is not going to account for that.
这不会说明这一点。
You have to write the better sweep line algorithm.
您必须编写更好的扫掠线算法。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: What I'm talking about
教授：我在说什么
now will make your range index faster.
现在将使您的范围索引更快。
Or it makes your range index simpler to implement.
或者，它使范围索引更易于实现。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: This is magic behind the scenes that
教授：这是幕后的魔法，
makes your code smaller.
使您的代码更小。
You still have to implement the sweep line algorithm that
您仍然必须实现扫线算法
makes sure that when you a range query
确保当您进行范围查询时
it will either return less false positives or ideally no false
它将返回较少的误报或理想情况下不返回错误
positives.
积极的。
And then the code will be faster.
然后代码会更快。
But then when you do that, you'll
但是当你这样做的时候，你会
see that it's still slow because the range index
看到它仍然很慢，因为范围索引
that we have here isn't optimal.
我们在这里并不是最佳选择。
Why isn't the range index here optimal, by the way?
顺便说一下，为什么这里的范围索引不是最佳的？
What can I improve about it?
我对此有何改进？
AUDIENCE: Add and remove.
听众：添加和删除。
PROFESSOR: Add and remove.
教授：添加和删除。
OK.
好。
We're using the comparison model because it's
我们正在使用比较模型，因为它
convenient to use the comparison model.
方便使用比较模型。
You have complex objects to implement those six methods
您有复杂的对象来实现这六个方法
that you see in key wire pair and bam.
在钥匙线对和bam中看到的
You can do comparisons, you can use any data structure
您可以进行比较，可以使用任何数据结构
or algorithm that assume a comparison model.
或采用比较模型的算法。
What's the penalty of the comparison model?
比较模型的代价是什么？
What's the problem with it?
有什么问题吗？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: It will be slower, or it will never
听众：会变慢，或者永远不会
be faster than the [INAUDIBLE].
比[听不清]快。
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
If I want to do a sort that is n log n.
如果我要执行的排序是n log n。
And if I want to do a search that is theta what?
如果我要搜索theta怎么办？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Now what are the best bounds that they have for these
教授：现在，他们的最佳界限是什么
if we can go outside the comparison model?
是否可以超越比较模型？
Just to see if you guys are paying attention in lecture.
只是为了看看你们在讲课时是否注意。
So best running time for sort if we
所以最好的运行时间来排序，如果我们
don't have to use the comparison model.
不必使用比较模型。
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
PROFESSOR: n.
教授：
OK.
好。
Best running time for search if we
如果我们能提供最佳搜索时间
don't to use the comparison model.
不要使用比较模型。
AUDIENCE: It's order one with [INAUDIBLE].
听众：用[听不清]订购一。
PROFESSOR: Order one, with hashing.
教授：一阶，带有哈希。
Can you do any better than that?
你能做得更好吗？
AUDIENCE: You can code it as zero.
听众：您可以将其编码为零。
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
PROFESSOR: Sort has to output an array
教授：排序必须输出一个数组
of elements so it can be faster than order n.
元素，因此它可以比n阶更快。
Search has to output yes or no so it has to output
搜索必须输出是或否，因此必须输出
something so it has to be order one.
东西，所以它必须是第一。
So this is as fast as it gets, we're
所以这是最快的，我们
definitely not going to go faster than that.
绝对不会比这快。
We have this extra log n factor that we
我们有这个额外的log n因子
pay if we use the comparison model if we don't collect
如果我们不使用比较模型，则付款
more information about our keys.
有关我们钥匙的更多信息。
But in return we have the convenience
但是作为回报，我们有方便
that all we have to do is establish
我们要做的就是建立
an ordering relationship.
排序关系。
Does it make sense?
是否有意义？
Cool.
凉。
Let's try to talk about the list pseudocode, which
让我们尝试谈谈列表伪代码，
you might have seen on the pset before.
您可能以前在pset上看到过。
And that's on the last page here.
那是这里的最后一页。
I can't give you a proof of why it works,
我无法证明它为何有效，
but we can work together to figure out how it works
但是我们可以一起努力弄清楚它是如何工作的
and get an intuitive understanding.
并获得直观的理解。
Let's get the keys here and let's
让我们在这里获取钥匙，然后
assume we're using a regular BSD for implementing a range index.
假设我们使用常规BSD来实现范围索引。
I'm going to put my keys in a BSD.
我将把密钥放在BSD中。
8, 3, 2, 5.
8、3、2、5
OK.
好。
List those two things.
列出这两件事。
LCA and no list.
LCA，没有列表。
Right.
对。
What's LCA?
什么是LCA？
Suppose I want to list all the keys between one and six.
假设我要列出一到六个之间的所有键。
First I'm going to call LCA and get some answer
首先，我将打电话给LCA并得到一些答案
and then I'm going to call node list.
然后我要调用节点列表。
What's the answer for LCA?
LCA的答案是什么？
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: Node at three.
听众：节点在三点。
Key value three.
关键值三。
PROFESSOR: What is this?
教授：这是什么？
What's LCA?
什么是LCA？
It's OK to give out an answer to a dumb question on the pset.
可以在pset上回答一个愚蠢的问题，这是可以的。
So LCA is lowest common ancestor.
因此，LCA是最低的共同祖先。
Very good.
很好。
It's the lowest common ancestor of what?
它是什么的最低祖先？
AUDIENCE: Subtree of values that should be returned nodeless.
受众：应无节点返回的值的子树。
PROFESSOR: So usually you have two nodes in a tree
教授：所以通常您在一棵树上有两个节点
and you want to return the LCA.
并且您想返回LCA。
If I want to find out the LCA of 2 and 5, that is 3.
如果我想找出2和5的LCA，那就是3。
If I want to find out the LCA of 2 and 13, that's 8.
如果我想找出2和13的LCA，那就是8。
Now if the keys are not in the tree what does the LCA give me?
现在，如果密钥不在树中，那么LCA会给我什么？
AUDIENCE: It's where they would be.
听众：这就是他们要去的地方。
PROFESSOR: It's where they would be if they were inserted.
教授：如果将它们插入，它将在这里。
Right.
对。
So 1 would be inserted here and 6 would be inserted here.
因此，将在此处插入1，在此处插入6。
And then their LCA is indeed 3.
然后他们的LCA确实为3。
What does that tell me?
这告诉我什么？
Why is that useful?
为什么这样有用？
AUDIENCE: You can cut off a bunch of the rest of the tree
听众：您可以砍掉一棵树的其余部分
so you don't have to look at that.
因此您不必去看。
PROFESSOR: A bunch of, or the rest of the tree?
教授：是一棵树还是其余的树？
AUDIENCE: The rest of the tree.
听众：树的其余部分。
PROFESSOR: The rest of the tree.
教授：这棵树的其余部分。
So if 1 is here and 6 is here, then I
所以如果1在这里6在这里，那么我
know that all the keys-- sorry, so 3 is to the left of 8
知道所有键-对不起，所以8的左边是3
so all the keys to the right of 8
所以所有键在8的右边
are going to be bigger than 6, for example.
例如，将大于6。
Right.
对。
Because 6 is here and it's under 8.
因为6在这里，而在8以下。
I can throw this away.
我可以扔掉它。
Now if this would be to the left of something else,
现在，如果这是其他内容的左侧，
because 1 is here I know that all the keys
因为这里是1我知道所有的钥匙
to the left side of that thing would be smaller than 1.
那东西的左侧小于1。
This subtree has to have all the keys between 1 and 6.
该子树必须具有1到6之间的所有键。
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: You don't have to move 8, right?
听众：您不必搬8，对吗？
Where would you move 8?
您将8移到哪里？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So we only look at the subtree rooted at LCA.
因此，我们仅查看根于LCA的子树。
LCA is passed as an argument to node list,
LCA作为参数传递给节点列表，
and node list seems to do sort of an-- this
和节点列表似乎做了一个
is a pre-ordered traversal.
是预定的遍历。
You look at the key, you look at the left node,
看一下键，看一下左节点，
at the left subtree, you look at the right subtree.
在左侧的子树中，您可以看到右侧的子树。
Except there is some magic there and in some cases
除了那里有魔法，在某些情况下
it doesn't go and look.
它不会去看。
Let's see what would a good case where it doesn't go and look
让我们来看看不去看看的好情况
like.
喜欢。
Let's get the same tree.
让我们得到同一棵树。
Suppose I want to do a list between 4 and 11--
假设我要在4到11之间列出一个清单，
sorry between 4 and 10.
抱歉，在4点到10点之间。
We'll the LCA of 4 and 10?
我们的LCA为4和10？
AUDIENCE: Eight.
听众：八。
PROFESSOR: OK, so node list would have to start here.
教授：好的，因此节点列表必须从这里开始。
Suppose I'm here and I go to 3.
假设我在这里，然后转到3。
I know 3 is smaller than 4.
我知道3比4小。
Do I want to go left?
我要走吗
Everything to the left of 3 is smaller than 4.
3左侧的所有内容都小于4。
This entire subtree can be pruned.
可以修剪整个子树。
Now suppose I'm on the right side and I'm at the 11.
现在假设我在右侧，我在11号。
11 is bigger than 10, do I want to go right?
11大于10，我要走对吗？
So if 11 is bigger than 10 I never
所以如果11大于10我就不会
want to go right because everything
想去正确的地方，因为一切
to the right of that is bigger.
在右边更大。
OK so this is how pruning works.
好的，这就是修剪的方式。
Now if I'm at 3, can I stop?
现在如果我三点钟，我可以停下来吗？
I can't stop and exit completely because on the right side of 3
我无法完全停止并退出，因为在3的右侧
I might have keys that are bigger than three
我可能有大于三个的钥匙
and that are in my interval.
而这是我的间隔。
And in this example that seems to be the case.
在这个例子中似乎是这样。
Let's look very quickly at the intuitive way
让我们快速看一下直观的方式
of analyzing the running time for this.
分析运行时间。
Suppose I have my LCA up here and suppose
假设我在这里有我的LCA，并假设
I go on a path from LCA to L and then-- let's
我走了一条从LCA到L的道路，然后-
not worry about the right, about h. h is somewhere here,
不用担心权利，关于h。 h在这里
the case is going to be symmetric.
这种情况将是对称的。
When I go down the path, after I go here would I ever want to go
当我沿着这条路走之后，我会想去
left?
剩下？
If this node is before a right turn then
如果此节点在右转弯之前
I know that l is going to be bigger than that node.
我知道我会比那个节点大。
Right?
对？
So I'm never going to take a left turn.
所以我永远不会左转。
This subtree be pruned, this subtree will be pruned,
该子树将被修剪，该子树将被修剪，
this subtree will be pruned.
该子树将被修剪。
Now if I go right here, what happens?
现在，如果我去这里，会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: It's node--
听众：这是节点
PROFESSOR: All the nodes here are
教授：这里的所有节点都是
going to be between l and LCA.
将在l和LCA之间。
LCA is smaller or equal to h so all these nodes here
LCA小于或等于h，所以这里所有这些节点
are guaranteed to be nodes that come out in my list.
保证是我列表中列出的节点。
All right, why am I doing this?
好吧，为什么我要这样做？
I was saying before that I absolutely
我之前说过我绝对
have to have an order i because I
我必须下订单，因为我
have to produce the output list.
必须产生输出列表。
If we look at the lines three and four,
如果我们看第三和第四行，
line four outputs a key right?
第四行输出一个密钥对吗？
Line four is definitely order i and line three
第四行肯定是我和第三行
is an if condition so we know for sure
是一个if条件，因此我们可以肯定地知道
that line four is only going to execute
那第四行只会执行
four keys that are between l and h.
l和h之间的四个键。
This algorithm is going to visit some nodes in the tree.
该算法将访问树中的某些节点。
For example, if I have a list of 4 and 10 it's going to visit 8,
例如，如果我有一个清单4和10，那么它将访问8，
it's going to visit 3, 5, and 11.
它将访问3、5和11。
And for some of the nodes that are visited
对于某些被访问的节点
it's going to output them.
将输出它们。
Right this guy gets output and this guy gets output.
对，这个家伙得到输出，这个家伙得到输出。
The nodes that are outputs are order i.
输出的节点是顺序i。
Those are already covered in the i term.
第i项已经涵盖了这些内容。
And in order to get the running time what I need to know
为了获得运行时间，我需要知道
is, how many nodes do I visit that are not
是，我要访问多少个不属于的节点
part of the output.
输出的一部分。
Because if I end up visiting the entire tree then
因为如果我最终访问整棵树，
that's order n plus i.
那是n加i的命令。
So order n.
因此订购n。
But if I only end up visiting a few nodes outside of the output
但是如果我最后只访问输出之外的几个节点
then that might be a lot better.
那可能会好得多。
And here I'm trying to argue that I will only
在这里，我试图证明我只会
visit a few notes the outside the path.
在路径外访问一些笔记。
In fact, for every node I'm going
实际上，我要去的每个节点
to visit at most of the node and the node at its left.
访问最多的节点及其左侧的节点。
And then everything to the right of the path is between l and h,
然后，路径右边的所有东西都在l和h之间，
so everything to the right is going to be output.
因此，将输出右侧的所有内容。
Everything here is in order i and everything here
这里的一切都是为了我和这里的一切
is visited in that output.
在该输出中被访问。
And potentially everything on the path as well.
以及路径上的所有潜在内容。
So what's the height of a path in a binary search tree?
那么二叉搜索树中路径的高度是多少？
Regular binary search tree?
常规的二进制搜索树？
OK, and worst case.
好，最坏的情况。
So worst case the height is order n.
因此，最坏的情况是高度为n阶。
But we usually call it height because on average, at least,
但是我们通常称其为高度，因为至少
it's log n.
它是日志n。
It's somewhere between n and log n.
它介于n和log n之间。
What is the running time for lists in a binary search tree?
二叉搜索树中的列表的运行时间是多少？
If you buy this argument here.
如果您在这里购买此参数。
What is the running time?
几点钟了？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: You could say n plus i and you're perfectly correct.
教授：您可以说n加i，这是完全正确的。
But we can make it a bit better.
但是我们可以做得更好。
What's the height of this path?
这条路的高度是多少？
AUDIENCE: h.
听众：h。
PROFESSOR: H. What's the running time?
教授：H.几点钟了？
AUDIENCE: h plus i.
听众：h加i。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Cool.
凉。
Does this make sense at all?
这有道理吗？
Is this too complicated?
这太复杂了吗？
AUDIENCE: That's the running time for what?
听众：那是什么时间？
PROFESSOR: This is the running time for lists.
教授：这是列表的运行时间。
All right so, questions?
好吧，有问题吗？
Is this too far out?
这太远了吗？
Did I lose you guys completely?
我完全失去了你们吗？
Makes perfect sense.
很有道理。
I like that.
我喜欢。
AUDIENCE: It's oder n plus i because it
听众：更好，因为我
could have up to any nodes on it, right?
最多可以有任何节点，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: And then it's order i because you
听众：然后是命令我，因为你
have to add that [INAUDIBLE] of nodes anyway.
无论如何都必须添加该[INAUDIBLE]节点。
It's order h.
订单h。
PROFESSOR: I'm saying that it's a binary search tree of height
教授：我是说这是一棵高度很高的二叉搜索树
h and if h is better than n then I'm
h，如果h优于n，那么我就是
going to do much better than n and that's
比n要好得多，那就是
why I'm putting that h there.
为什么我把那个放在那里。
AUDIENCE: OK, that makes sense.
听众：好的，这很有道理。
I think it's just a ltitle confusing at that part,
我认为那只是一个令人困惑的标题，
but the [INAUDIBLE] makes sense because of course
但是[听不清]是有道理的，因为
that's a smaller node you're not going
那是一个较小的节点，您不会
to look at the left portion you're
看你的左边部分
going to look at the right because it's bigger
要看正确的，因为它更大
than your smaller [INAUDIBLE], right?
比你的小[听不清]，对吗？
So if you go to the right, that means that--
因此，如果您向右走，那意味着-
PROFESSOR: Here I know that l is on the left, right?
教授：我在这里知道我在左边，对不对？
So l is smaller than this key.
所以l小于此键。
Everything to the right of this key is between l and LCA.
该键右侧的所有内容都在l和LCA之间。
LCA is smaller or equal to h.
LCA小于或等于h。
Everything here is between l and h,
这里的一切都在l和h之间，
so all the nodes here are going to be output.
因此这里的所有节点都将被输出。
All the nodes here count as i.
这里的所有节点都算作i。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: Now when I turn left here, this is smaller than l.
教授：现在，当我在这里左转时，它比l小。
This is smaller than l because l is on the right.
它比l小，因为l在右边。
This thing is going to be pruned.
这东西将被修剪。
So I will visit the parent, this node, and that's it.
因此，我将访问父节点，该节点，仅此而已。
I'm not going to look down.
我不会看不起。
And this is how the nodes look like.
这就是节点的样子。
Everything that's to the left of the path
路径左侧的所有内容
is not visited, everything that's to the right it open.
没有被访问，它右边的所有内容都会打开。
Any more questions?
还有其他问题吗？
I hope you get it right on pset then.
希望您随后在pset上正确使用它。
Thanks guys.
多谢你们。